Marines will lead Rukh and Shagadam.
歩兵隊はルッハームとシャガード
Horsemen - Daryun. The Flying Squad - Kisvard.
騎兵隊はダリューン
別動隊はキシュワードが率いる
短期決戦には城内への騎兵隊の突撃は不可欠だ
To deal quickly and decisively,
riders have to break the lock.
そのために　まずは城壁の侵略
To do this, you must first destroy its walls.
The problem is, what the enemies are busy at this time.
問題は　その間の敵軍の行動だが…
I've already made all the possible options for the development of the situation.
あらゆる状況は私の頭の中に想定済みでございます
The most problematic is the situation,
最も厄介な状況は　敵軍が数に物を言わせてきた場合ですが
when the enemy uses most of its forces ...
But we have carefully thought of everything.
策は抜かりありません
ダリューン
Darjun.
Yes I know.
ああ　分かっている
頼んだぞ
I rely on you.
Trust me.
お任せください
必ずや殿下に吉報をお持ちします
I will bring you good news.
戦いが始まってしまえば　あとは皆に任せるしかない
Since the beginning of the battle
I will only have to rely on people.
私にも何かできることがあれば…
If I could do something ...
Prince, you are the banner of the army.
殿下はこの軍の御旗
後方にて戦果を待つことも指揮官の務めです
Wait for the results of the fight in the rear -
It is also part of a team of debt.
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流
更多中日双语字幕，尽在www.kamigami.org 及微博@诸神字幕组
General wage kingdom Lyusitaniya, Mr. Silver mask, Hermes
勇敢なるルシタニアの戦士たちよ
Lyusitanii brave warriors!
According to the imperial decree of His Majesty Innosentisa,
私はイノケンティス陛下の勅命により　連合軍１０万の指揮を仰せつかった
I entrusted the command of the combined forces of a hundred thousand people!
よいか
Listen!
神聖なる聖マヌエル城におけるこの一戦
In the battle that will take place in the holy castle of St. Emmanuel,
we must win!
我らは必ず勝利を手にせねばならない
kaze ga zawameki kudaketa kimochi
Quiet wind awakens emotions and broken,
日听&翻译
小伍
sora
兰樱
校对
小江
mam
misukashi teru you de furueta yo
I see through everything and I shiver.
michita tsuki no hi touboe no inochi
In the sky a full moon, and the city comes howling:
片源
Rei
时间轴
Usagi&雪糕
压制
Coolkid
mada oite kanaide yo
"Please do not throw until we have!"
bokura torikaeseru ka na iro tsuki no sora
Will we return to the old sky, painted in the colors?
hokori mamire no yume mai agete
Rise in the dance vortex hourglass Sci,
kobushi wo nigittanara
to be clamped in their fists.
ima hashire hashire tsuji kaze ni natte
Now run forward, run forward, and stand by the whirlwind,
rettou zetsubou issai fukitobashite iku
feelings of hopelessness and despair of sour cream on the way.
oikakenakya saigo no tobira
Clears the currently last track.
nando chittatte dai gyakuten
Let all break, we will rise again,
kono goe ga shagare tatte inorinouta todoketai yo
even a hoarse voice will sing songs and prayers.
tarinai bokura de shinji teta sekai wo ubaetara
Even insignificant, as we will be able to capture the whole world in which to believe.
madamada madamada make rarenai
We have still not yet been defeated!
Chapter XXIII
地上のあらゆるものが本来ルシタニアのものだ
All that is in the land rightfully belongs Lyusitanii!
And Parsis army that does not understand,
それを理解しないパルス軍こそ　略奪者に他ならん
it's just a bunch of looters!
正義は我らにある
Justice for us!
パルスは我ら神の信徒から略奪しようとする悪魔だ
Parsa - it is the devil who destroys the faith of our God!
そうだ
Right!
Destroy the heathen!
異教徒どもを滅ぼせ
我が軍の兵は１０万　敵よりも勝っている
We have a strong army of a hundred thousand, a numerically superior enemy!
And I will command,
指揮を執るのはアトロパテネにてパルスを敗北せしめたこの私だ
the man who prevented the Pars and destroyed at Atropatena!
私に従うがいい　勝利を約束してやろう
Follow me! I guarantee you victory!
Castle of Emmanuel
General kingdom Parsis, Rukh
攻城車　破城槌　前へ
Forts and artillery moving out!
It..
あれは…
サーム殿
Mr. Saam!
どうして
Why?
Can not be...
そんな…
栄光あるマルズバーンがルシタニアの手先に身を落とすとは
Known and respected marzban
General kingdom Parsis, Shagadam
decided to become a pawn Lyusitanii ...
報告いたします
Reporting.
聖マヌエル城の城壁はいまだ破れる気配なし
The walls of the castle of St. Emmanuel
yet show no signs of weakness.
加えて　兵士の一部に動揺が起こっています
In addition, people have started to take.
Due to the fact that there Saam?
サーム殿がいるからか
Yes.
はい
マルズバーンとして名高く
Famed marzban,
城塞の守りにおいて右に出る者なしといわれる男だ
and they say, no one better than he knows how to protect the fortress.
兵たちの動揺もしかたない
It is no wonder that people are worried.
殿下…
Prince...
It's okay, Elam.
大丈夫だ　エラム
サームが従兄弟殿のもとにいるのは分かっていたこと
We already know that Saam went after my cousin.
それでも戦わねばならぬ
But we still have to fight.
私自身が選んだ道だから
For the sake of the path that I chose.
I apologize.
失礼いたします
Lord Holy Emmanuel, Barkasion castle
エトワールか
Etoile ...
伯爵様　この度の戦　私も兵たちの前線に立って戦おうと思います
Monsieur le Comte,
I also want to stand on the front lines and fight the battle.
Wait. If I let you into a dangerous ...
待ちなさい　お前を危険にさらすことは…
敵は異教徒です
Our enemy - the pagans!
この世に正しきイアルダボートの教えを広め
In order to spread the faith and the teaching of Yaldabaoth World
そのために異教徒と戦うのが我らルシタニア騎士の役目
we fight with them!
It is the duty of the Knights Lyusitanii!
我が身の危険などいといませぬ　この身がどうなろうと
I'm ready and I want to risk his life!
And no matter what will happen to me!
そのようなことを言うものではない
No need to say that.
たとえ伯爵様のお許しが頂けなくとも　私は戦いに参加いたします
Even if you do not give permission,
I still go to battle.
I apologize in advance if you believe it is arrogance.
思い上がりに聞こえましたら　お詫び申し上げます
それほどまでに異教徒との戦いを望んでおりますこと
Please do understand how much I want to fight with the Gentiles.
お察しください
Why does not he understand me?
なぜ伯爵様はお分かりにならない
異教徒の王を滅ぼせる好機なのだ
This is a great opportunity to destroy the King of the Gentiles.
この身を犠牲にしても
Even if you have to sacrifice yourself ...
私も前線で戦いたかったなぁ
I also wanted to fight on the front line ...
Say, the Alfred.
のう　アルフリードよ
What?
何
You of Zot clan, right?
お主　ゾット族じゃったな
そうだよ　それがどうかした
Right. And what difference does it make?
Clan Zot - nomadic people,
ゾット族は本来　パルス王宮の権威に縛られぬ遊牧の民
who do not recognize the authority of Parsis.
だが　お主はずっと共に戦ってくれておる
But you all this time fighting with us.
Perhaps.
まあね　銀仮面はおやじの敵だし…
Silver mask killed my father ...
それに　私　殿下のお役に立ちたいしね
Besides, I want to be useful to the prince.
ナルサス卿のためにかな
For the sake of Mr. Narsusa?
Yes. But not the only reason.
うん　でも　それだけじゃなくて
アルスラーン殿下は何かすごいことをやってくれそうな気がするんだ
I think Prince Arslan is capable of amazing things.
Just look how my Narsus cares about him.
なんたって　私のナルサスがあんなに気にかけてるんだもの
ファランギースもそう思うでしょ
You think so too, Farangis?
そうじゃな
Perhaps.
王都の奪還　復興　そして　国の改革
Return capital to restore it and to carry out reforms in the country ...
まだ１４歳でしかない殿下には重すぎる任務じゃ
He is only fourteen, but Prince is already a burden so heavy.
Although the Prince seems to overpower it.
だが　殿下ならそれができると感じさせてくれる
That he can get it done from the Parsis perfect kingdom.
あのお方ならば　パルスを望ましの王土に変えることができるやもしれん
A few hours later in the siege,
攻城開始から数刻
パルス兵たちに疲労が見えはじめた頃
when soldiers Parsis began to gradually get tired,
great changes have taken place on the battlefield.
戦況が大きく動いた
門が…
Door...
Why?
なんで
とにかく攻め込め
Charge on!
Boring things!
まどろっこしいわ
ヒルメス殿下　アルスラーンの首　このザンデが持ち帰ってみせますぞ
Prince Hermes!
Look! I Zande, will come back to you along with the head Arslan!
Mr. Daryun seems to be the enemy's cavalry came.
ダリューン卿　敵騎兵隊が出たようだ
おお
Yes.
Victory will be ours! Yasasuiin!
我が軍に勝利を　ヤシャスィーン
Discover the power of our riders!
我らパルス騎兵の力を知れ
お前はパルスの一軍を率いる将だ　死ぬな
You are a general who leads soldiers Parsis.
Do not you dare die!
I do not need your help!
お前の助けなどなくとも
単純なぶつかり合いでは　数で劣る我が軍が不利だ
In a simple collision of two forces
army with fewer people losing.
キシュワードたちの方がうまくいっていればよいが
Hopefully, Kisvarda and his men are all well ...
You still came.
やはり来たか
サーム殿
Mr. Saam ...
Soldiers Parsis ?!
パルス兵…
Penetrate into the underground course of the lock and open the gates from the inside ...
水路から城内に侵入し　内から門を開ける
I guess that you conceive it, but ...
そのつもりだったのだろうが
双刀将軍キシュワードの首　貴様らごときに取られるほど安くはない
General two swords Kisvard
not so weak that people like you, it overpowered!
Attack Together!
一斉にかかれ
And we attack!
俺たちも行くぞ
サーム殿
Mr. Saam, you pride Parsis knights.
パルスの誇り高き騎士たるあなたが
何故アルスラーン殿下の王道を阻もうとする
Why do you get up on the way to the throne Prince Arslan?
ヒルメス様のためだ
Prince of the Hermes.
俺くらいはあの方と共にあらねば
He deserves that at least I was on his side.
What do you know about what made Prince Hermes ?!
ヒルメス王子が何をしたか分かっているのか
王都に攻め入り　滅ぼしたのだぞ
Invaded the capital, destroy it!
I know!
分かっている
ならば
Then...
今は怒りと復讐心に取りつかれているが　いずれ　それも覚めよう
Now he is obsessed with rage and desire for revenge,
but it will pass.
その後は必ずやよき王として　あの方はパルスを導ける
And then it becomes obligatory
worthy of a king for Parsis!
Obsessed with the struggle for the throne, he makes his own people to suffer.
王位に取りつかれ　自国の民を苦しめた者を
Those who recognize this king ?!
誰が王と認めようか
In terms of numbers and other
兵の数など　我が軍の騎兵隊が優勢かと
our riders a clear advantage.
また　水路の守りにはサーム様が向かっています
And Mr. Saam went to the defense of the underground passage.
分かった　下がれ
Good. Free.
There is.
はっ
ザンデめ　勝手なまねを
Bloody Zande. I decided svoevolnichat ...
Lions ...
アルスラーン…
Humiliation and hardships I experienced that day ...
今日まで俺が味わってきた屈辱　辛酸
必ずや　貴様にも同じものを味わわせてやる
I'll make sure to try them and you!
蛮族どもが
Damned barbarians!
神の栄光あれ
Glory to our God!
逃がすな
Do not miss them!
神の名の下に
In the name of our God!
お前らの神の名なんざ知らねぇよ
If I know the name of your God.
苦戦しているようだな
It seems, help is needed.
悔い改め　イアルダボート教に改宗せよ
Repent and accept faith Yaldabaoth!
そうすれば　争いなど…
And then the fight ...
ふざけるな
Do not put!
くたばれ
Die!
狂信者が
Fanatics!
なぜ理解できんのだ
Why do you not understand ?!
なっ
What?..
あいつは…
Is he...
あのときの
The same! ..
なぜ　あんな所に？
What is he doing here?
絶対に食い止めろ
Reflect any cost!
殿下をお守りせよ
Protect the prince!
どけ
From the road!
誰か止めろ
Stop it anyone!
敵の本陣は目の前だ
The main enemy camp ahead!
あったぞ
At last.
突っ込め
We burst!
Lions!
アルスラーン
Your head will be mine!
その首　もらった
誰もいません
There's nobody here!
なんだと
What?!
退避
Retreat!
謀ったな
We were deceived!
この本陣は見せかけか
This camp was for show.
殿下　以前お話しした戦法の第一歩を覚えていらっしゃいますか
Prince, remember our conversation?
On the first step in a major strategy?
もちろんだ
Of course.
自分たちの望む場所に敵の兵力を集中させる…　だろう
Forcing the enemy to concentrate their forces where we need to.
Right?
一度退却し　態勢を立て直して…
Step back for a while, and then regroup ...
ペシャワール近くで戦って以来だな
We have not seen you after the Battle of Peshavarda.
ダリューン
Darjun!
あの崖から落ちても死なぬとは　頑丈なヤツめ
So, even a fall from a cliff you did not kill ...
Living podlets.
降伏しろ　今度はしとめるぞ
Give up! This time, I'll kill you for sure!
それは俺のセリフだ
These are my words!
お前は俺が殺さねばならぬ
I have to personally kill you!
父　カーラーンのために
For the sake of his father, Harlan!
父上は正統の王への忠誠心ゆえに
Out of a sense of loyalty to the present king,
ルシタニアに膝を屈する辛酸をなめた
he had to bow to force through Lyusitaniey!
その屈辱と汚名を負ったまま　お前に殺されたのだ
And under the pressure of humiliation and shame
He died at your hands!
だが　ヒルメス様がパルスの王となったとき
But when the Prince becomes King Hermes Parsis,
父上の汚名はすすがれる
father's name will be cleared!
我らこそが真の忠臣だと証明されよう
And it proves that we are loyal subjects!
さすが周辺諸国から恐れられ　東方国境にこの者ありといわれた騎士だ
What I was expecting from the knights who are afraid of our neighbors
and is known as the keeper of the eastern border.
お主を敵に回したくはなかったがな
I would not want you to have the enemies.
Have you been guarding the royal capital of Parsa.
俺もパルスの王都を長く守ってきたあなたと
このような形で戦いたくはなかった
I also would not like to fight like that.
しかたあるまい
That's that.
我々は道を異にしてしまった
We had to go separate ways.
一国に二王なし
One kingdom does not run two kings.
残酷であろうと　それが千古の鉄則
No matter how badly it sounds, but it has always been steadfast rule.
しかり
Yes!
故に我らは　ただ己の信じるもののために戦うのみ
Then we'll just have to fight for what one believes!
サーム様
Mr. Saam!
お守りしろ
Protect it!
ここだ
They are here!
父上の悲願　ヒルメス様の戴冠を邪魔はさせん
The father had long dreamed
Crown Prince of Hermes! And I will not let interfere!
似ているな
We are similar.
俺も　お前も
You and me.
そして　カーラーン殿も
And Mr. Harlan.
ただ信じる主のために戦うことしかできぬ男だ
We are people who are forced to only
to conquer the lords and masters
お前が父を語るな
Do not talk about my father!
カーラーン殿とは何度も共に戦場に出たことがあった
Many times I went to the battlefield with Mr. Harlan.
尊敬に値する騎士だった
He was a knight, worthy of respect.
父の汚名をすすぐため　ヒルメス様の王道のため
For the sake of cleansing the father's name!
For the coronation of Prince Hermes
お前は俺が討ち取る
I will destroy you!
その意気や良し
I appreciate the courage.
仕える主が違っていなければ　存外お前とは気が合っていたやもしれん
If we had not served by different people,
We could be soulmates.
お前は…
You!
お前たちには　まだまだ血を流してもらわねばならん
We need you to shed more blood.
消えた
Disappeared ...
It seems that the enemy is still seduced by our false camp.
敵はうまく偽の陣地に誘い込まれたようだな
ああ　これで　我らが優勢に…
Yes, and it will give us an advantage ...
偽の陣地に誘い込まれたルシタニア兵は　ほぼ壊滅したもようです
Lyusitanii troops, who came to the false camp
virtually destroyed.
これで敵戦力を削ることができました
Now we can deal with the enemy forces.
残る問題は城門ですが…
There are still the gates of the castle, but ...
Stop them!
やめろ
なんだ
What is it?
行かせるな
Do not miss!
エラム　殿下を
Elam, Prince.
ルシタニア兵か
Soldiers Lyusitani?
そこか　アルスラーン
You're here, Arslan ?!
殿下
Prince!
お主は…
You...
なぜだ
Why?
なぜ　お前がここにいる
Why are you here?
お…お前のような小僧の首はいらん
M-I do not want your head!
隠れ潜む卑怯者　アルスラーン王子はどこだ
Cowardly hiding scum ...
Where Prince Arslan ?!
どういうことだ
What does it mean?
まさか…
Really ...
私が　アルスラーンだ
I
Lion.
YakuSub Studio
kimi ga deatta kokoro wa kitto
All the souls that you could meet on the way,
translation Mu_Cool
hitotsu datte machigai janai
certainly it was pure and innocent,
Editorial Harushechka
onaji yume wo daite
We kept the same dream.
Making Weekend
michi wo tagaeta hito wo omotta
People walking different paths,
nozarashi no akogare wo kakagete susumu kouya
killed all my hopes and desires revive again.
hohoemi mo sono namida mo
Smile on his face, tears running down her cheeks,
koko ni suteteyukenai kara
If you want to go ahead, they should not be forgotten.
kage wo daite shiroku takaku
Covered by the shadow of the summer, so white and immense,
namonaki boku to kimi no hata
our with you nameless flag flies.
mada hatenaku tsudzuku kono mich ino kanata ni
There, on the road, which extends an endless path,
tatta hitotsu no hikari wo sen no kokoro ni
There is one bright light, and with it a thousand souls.
miageru sora wo shinjiteru
Believe in the sky above his head,
michibiku hoshi wo higashi no takami ni sashishimesu yo
there putevodnaâ our star in the east, ee do not engage.
yume wa kono te de kanaeru
And their cherished dream in flesh forces.
ヤシャスィーン
Jasasuiin! '
彼らは突進した
prokričali them.
槍を水平に構え　剣や戦斧を振りかざし
Rose spears, swords were bare,
石畳に馬蹄を轟かせて
and there was the sound of hooves of their horses.
次回　決戦
Next time:. "Decisive battle"
Chapter XXIV
少年は　そして王となる
And so the guy would be King.